

BILAL AL TAKI

Doctor Data Scientist and Al

- bilal.altaki.math@gmail.com
 Homepage LinkedIn
 GitHub
- January 2023 with possibility before (to discuss)

EDUCATION

Ph.D. in applied mathematics Grenoble-Alpes University

2013 - 2016

France

Studying problems related to fluid mechanics: Oceanography, Gas dynamics.

Master degree in mathematics Lebanese University & Nantes University

2011 - 2013

CERTIFICATIONS

• What is Data Science IBM.

(Syllabus, Certificate)

 Python for Data Science, AI & Development IBM.

(Syllabus, Certificate)

• Data Science with Python|IBM.

(Syllabus, Certificate)

• Machine Learning with Python.

(Syllabus, Certificate)

Machine Learning Specialization |
 Stanford.

(Syllabus, Certificate)

STRENGTHS

Data Visualization Python

Machine Learning Tensorflow

Deeplearning | Latex |

SQL

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Master Intership Co-Supervision of El Hassanieh at INRIA.
- Participation in the jury of "Advance Coucours" at EPITA.

LANGUAGES

Arabic French English



ABOUT ME

Having a PhD in applied mathematics, and being passionate about Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning related subjects with medium knowledge in this field, I am excited to apply my skills for solving real-world problems.

Currently, I am a visiting Researcher at TU Kaiserslautern.

EXPERIENCE

Research and Teaching Fellow | Sorbonne University

Sept 2021- Aug 2022

- Paris, FR
- Teaching mathematics courses for first and second academic year students.
- · Establishing new mathematical results concerning problems related to Landslide phenomena.

Researcher | Peking University

ä Jan 2020 - Aug 2021

- Beijing, CH
- · Developing new achievements to better understand the shoreline problem in environmental problems.

Research and Teaching Fellow | Sorbonne University

ä Jan 2019 – Aug 2019

- Paris, FR
- Teaching mathematics courses for first and second academic year students.
- Collaborating with colleagues during the CEMRACS'19 conference to studying the different numerical schemes devoted to the Compressible Navier-Stokes equations (used to model gas dynamics flow).

Researcher | INRIA

Sept 2017 - Dec 2018

- Paris, FR
- Teaching mathematics courses for Engineering students at Polytech Sorbonne.
- Developing new models to better understand the Tsunami phenomena.

PROJECTS

Here is a list of projects that I have done as a part of self-training on Data Science.

Data Science with Python | ? 2022

The aim of this project is to fit a linear regression or a Ridge Regression model to predict the price using the list of features given on a dataset which contains house sale prices for King County.

Machine Learning with Python | • 2022

In this project, we use classification models such as K Nearest Neighbor(KNN), Decision Tree, Support Vector Machine, or Logistic Regression to determine whether a loan is paid off or in based on a dataset about past loans.

Car's generation detection | • 2022

The aim of this project is to predict the generation (I or II) of some unknown generation cars based on the features of each generation.

SKILLS

- · Project management.
- Extraction and structuring of data.
- Development of artificial intelligence algorithms.
- Industrialization of artificial intelligence models in applications.
- Following latest advancements.